<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wayneJLee</title>
    <link>https://waynejlee.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on wayneJLee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 01:49:19 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://waynejlee.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Cybersecurity: Malaysia 
 Part 1</title>
      <link>https://waynejlee.com/posts/my-soc-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 01:49:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynejlee.com/posts/my-soc-p1/</guid>
      <description>This post will be a part of a 4-post series that documents some of the security issues present in Malaysian organizations.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write a post to highlight some of the common issues faced on our engagements with clients in Malaysia. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a meant to be a blame-and-shame post, but rather to help drive changes within Malaysian organizations.
Cybersecurity is a complex topic and requires a ton of planning, investment and execution to get right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero to OSCP</title>
      <link>https://waynejlee.com/posts/zero-to-oscp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 02:43:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynejlee.com/posts/zero-to-oscp/</guid>
      <description>Hello World! This post was written for those who are starting out and feeling overwhelmed by the breadth and depth of Infosec.
To make it as relatable as possible, I decided to make this a series of posts in which I go through the phases &amp;amp; challenges I faced through:
 OSCP OSWE Red Team Ops by Zero-Point Security  It&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that a majority of you readers come from the same background as I have, therefore this post won&amp;rsquo;t be a preparation guide per se.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://waynejlee.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 19:54:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynejlee.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Wayne Lee Technology Specialist @ Vigilant Asia Quick background:
 Dropped out of college to pursue Esports @ 19 Started my infosec journey in BD/Sales @ 27 Learned some Python around to automate work Decided to jump on HTB around July 2019 to learn how to hax stuff OSCP - Dec 2019 OSWE - May 2020  As a college dropout, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a formal education in Computer Science but I did tinker a lot with the computer ever since I was a kid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>